--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.cmct.tv
影片压制：死亡骑士　字幕调校：死亡骑士　招募Q号：324446465
字幕源：dottob
片名：血战钢锯岭
一个真实的故事
你可曾听过
Have you not heard?
耶和华是永恒之神
The Lord is the everlasting God,
创造地极之主
the Creator of the ends of the Earth.
他既不疲乏 也不困倦
He will not grow tired or weary,
他的智慧无人可揣度
and His understanding no one can fathom.
他赐力量予疲乏者
He gives strength to the weary
增能力予软弱者
and increases the power of the weak.
正值青春亦会疲惫困倦
Even youths grow tired and weary,
青年亦会绊倒跌跤
and young men stumble and fall.
但那些仰望上帝者
But those who hope in the Lord
必重新得力
will renew their strength.
他们必展翅翱翔如鹰
They will soar on wings like eagles.
他们必奔跑 而不疲倦
They will run and not grow weary.
他们必行走 而不跌倒
They will walk and not be faint.
德斯蒙德 坚持住
Desmond, hang on!
坚持住 德斯蒙德
Hang on, Desmond!
我们会带你离开这儿
We're going to get you out of here!
蓝脊山脉 弗吉尼亚州
十六年前
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
Desmond!
干嘛
What?
- 等等嘛 - 跟上嘛
- Wait up. - Catch up.
等等嘛 我有事要告诉你
Wait up, I've got something to tell you.
什么？哈尔
What, Hal?
到顶者赢
Race you to the top.
嘿 骗子
Hey! Cheater!
- 回头见 笨伯 - 嘿
- See you later, slowpoke. - Hey!
搭把手
Want a hand?
我能行
I got it.
下去吧
Sit down!
- 别闹 - 走你
- don't quit it. - You quit it.
上帝保佑
For Pete's sake.
嘿 离悬崖远点 该死的傻孩子
Hey! Get away from that ledge, you damn fool kids!
想摔断脖子吗
You're going to break your necks!
他们是多斯的儿子 跟老爹一样疯狂
It's them Doss kids. Crazy as their old man.
他们挖掘了杰克埋骨之地
They dug up the corner of Jackson and Main...
把他放在人行道上
Putting in a sidewalk...
你们现已认不出来啦
You boys wouldn't recognize it now.
告诉你 我怀疑他们会认出你
Mind you, I doubt they'd recognize you.
他们几乎认不出我 当我路过
They hardly know me when I walk by 'em.
好象我跟你一起死了
It's like I died with you.
好象我们从未存在过
It's like we boys never existed.
好了 今天就说这些
Well, that's all I got for you today.
用右手挡住他 德斯蒙德
Block him with your right, Desmond.
别打了 听到了吗
Stop it! Do you hear me?
- 他们干嘛打架 - 他们何需有理
- What are they fighting about? - When'd they ever need a reason?
汤姆 你能
Tom! do...
何必阻止而让我两个都打
Why stop 'em? Saves me whipping them both.
这样我只需打那个赢的
This way, I just whip the one that wins.
汤姆
Torn!
不
No!
噢 天啦
Oh, God.
汤姆 醒醒 你能听到吗
Tom! Wake up, can you hear me?
- 你怎么能这样 - 他听不到我
- What the hell have you done? - He can't hear me.
我们得拿些冰块
I'll get some ice.
- 把那个篮子拿开 - 好的
- You shift that basket. - I got it.
他在呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
哈尔 哈尔你能听到吗
Hal? Hal, can you hear me?
哈尔你能听到吗
Hal, can you hear me?
哈尔
Hal...
拜托 拜托
Come on. Come on.
他瞳孔在扩张
He's dilated.
哈尔
Hal...
《主祷文 十诫》
你做事不经大脑吗
What do you think you're doin'?
我现在必须打你 你知道规则
I'm gonna have to beat you now, you know the rules.
听到没 德斯蒙德
You hear me, Desmond?
第六诫 你不能杀人
- 德斯蒙德 - 汤姆 住手
- Desmond! - Tom, stop.
这样教育不了他
What's that gonna teach the boy?
他的暴行已经够多了
He's violent enough already.
好极了 赏他一个令人窒息的吻
Okay, fine, you go smother him in kisses.
告诉他这世界是个既柔软又温暖之处
You tell him the world's a soft and gentle place.
哈尔会好的
Hal's gonna be okay.
嘿
Hey.
我差点杀了他
I could have killed him.
是的 你差点
Yes, you could have.
谋杀是众恶之首
Murder, it's the worst sin of all.
取人性命
And to take another man's life,
则是最严重之罪在主眼里
that is the most egregious sin in the Lord's sight.
再没别的能令他更伤心
Nothing hurts his heart so much.
你听不懂人话吗？
Don't you understand English?
让我再说一次吗？
Do I have to tell you again?
你滚开 婆娘 否者我要动手了
You move, woman, or I will wallop you good and hard!
在闹什么呢 你没事吧 伯莎
What the hell's going on? You okay, Bertha?
你在意你自己的破事
You mind your own damned business!
去睡觉吧 汤姆
Go sleep it off, Tom.
我恨他
I hate him.
妈妈
Momma?
他为什么如此恨我们
Why does he hate us so much?
哦 他不恨我们
Oh, he don't hate us.
他恨自己
He hates himself
有时
sometimes.
你爸爸 我见过真实的他
Your daddy tonight, that ain't the real him.
我希望你了解他 就像战前我那样
I wish you knew him like I did, before the war.
十五年后
我们唱得如何？德斯蒙德
How'd we sound, Desmond?
就像天使 妈
Like a heavenly host of angels, Mom.
你知 撒谎可是罪 尤其在此地
Now, you know it's a sin to tell a lie, especially in this place.
我可从未说过她们是唱歌的天使
Well, I ain't never said they were singing angels.
外面怎么了？德斯蒙德
What's going on out there? Desmond!
继续 拉出来 拉出来
Get it up, get it up!
拖出来 拖吧
Drag him out. Just the tarp.
我打电话叫救护车
I'll phone an ambulance.
不 没时间了 找辆皮卡
No, no time. Joshua's pickup.
- 要快 - 好的
- Quick! - Okay.
林奇伯格医院
你会好的 伙计 你会好的
You're going to be fine now. You're going to be fine.
- 你是专家 - 我看看
- You're in good hands. - I see.
何处受伤
What have we got here?
动脉切断 拿些缝线来
It's a severed artery. Get some sutures.
好的 医生
Yes, doctor.
稍稍用力按住它 是你用此止血的
Put some pressure on it. Did you apply this tourniquet?
- 是的 先生 - 干得不错
- Yes, sir. - Nice work.
你可救了这孩子一命
You might have saved this boy's life.
- 你住我们这儿 - 你会好的
- You staying with us? - You're going to be okay.
你叫什么名字 孩子
What's your name, son?
吉尔伯特
Gilbert.
- 动手术？- 对 动手术
- Surgery? - Yeah, surgery.
住我们这儿 你会好的
Stay with us, you're gonna be okay.
你感觉痛吗？
You feel pain?
住这里 好吗？
Stay with us, okay?
部队体检在那边 这里是献血
Army physicals that way. This is for giving blood.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
哦不 那不是我的 我很好
Oh, no, that's not mine. I'm fine.
谢谢你的问询 女士
Thank you for asking though, ma'am.
你要什么
What do you need?
我的皮带
My belt.
我把它借给出车祸的男生
I lent it to the boy who had the accident.
没它我的裤子系不好
My pants don't hold up so good without it.
呃 我可没有你的皮带
Well, uh, I don't have your belt.
不 我知女士
No, I know that, ma'am. It's out there.
它仍在男生那儿
It's right out there with the boy still.
好吧
Okay.
我在此采血
I'm just here to take blood.
我给你我的
I'll give mine.
好吧 去那个房间 跟别人一起等
Okay, go to that room over there and wait with the others.
我会叫你
I'll call you.
那个 那个房间
That room.
你以前献过血吗 先生
You ever given blood before, Mr...
多斯
Doss.
但朋友们都叫我德斯蒙德 不 女士这是我第一次
But my friends call me Desmond. No, ma'am, this is my first time.
我总梦想成为医生 只是呢
I always dreamed about being a doctor. But, uh,
没念多少书
I didn't get much school.
可能有点头晕 采完后
You may be a little dizzy when we're done.
有人接你吗
Is somebody picking you up?
没 女士 我走回去
No, ma'am. Walking back.
你住哪儿
Where do you live?
福特哈姆 女士
Fort Hill, ma'am.
那挺远的
That's a ways.
五或六英里
No. Just five or six miles,
我穿过树林
but I cut through the woods.
那就七英里
It's seven that way!
必是因喜欢树林
You must really like the woods.
是的女士 确实是
Yes, ma'am. I sure do.
好吧 轻压此处
Okay, put some pressure here.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
再见
Bye.
这是要去哪儿？看起来整洁帅气
Where you going looking all spruced and nice?
去见昨天的人
Met someone yesterday.
医院护士
A nurse over at the hospital.
名叫多萝西舒特 我要娶她
Her name's Dorothy Schutte. I'm gonna marry her.
天啦 她知道吗
Goodness. Does she know that?
还没呢 不过快了
Well, not yet. She's about to.
你跟女人说过话吗？
You ever even spoken to a woman?
除了这个你妈妈之外
I mean, one that's not family.
跟她说过
Spoke to her.
- 既如此 给你兄弟来个大大的拥抱 - 哈尔
- Well, in that case, come give your brother a big hug. - Hal!
过来
Come here.
让你的油爪离我远点儿
Keep your greasy paws off of me.
祝我好运 妈妈
Wish me luck, Momma.
祝你好运
Good luck.
下一个
Next.
随便坐
Grab a seat.
你以前献过血吗
You ever given blood before?
是的 女士 我有
Yes, ma'am. I have.
你 皮带男
You're the belt man.
德斯蒙德 是的 女士
Desmond, yes, ma'am.
好吧 德斯蒙德 我们不能连续两天采你的血
Well, Desmond, we can't take your blood two days in a row.
那就好 可否拿回我的
Well, that's good. I came to get mine back.
- 你的啥 - 我的血 我想要回来
- You what? - My blood. I need it back.
那不行 不能把它还你
Well, it don't work like that, we can't just give it back to you.
好吧 你必需还
Well, you got to.
自从你用针扎了我 我就心跳加速
Ever since you stuck me with that needle, my heart's been beating real fast.
每次想到你则会跳得更快
Every time I think about you, it beats faster still.
我以前从未听过这话 好土
I never heard that one before. It's pretty corny.
是吗？
It is?
这是个耻辱 我练了一整夜
That's a shame, I done practiced that all night.
不好吗
No good?
我没那样说
I didn't say that.
有何差异？动脉跟静脉
What's the difference between an artery and a vein?
- 你说啥 - 男孩的车祸
- What are you talking about? - The boy's accident.
动脉喷血
Arteries spurt blood.
静脉呢
And veins?
流血
Bleed.
我觉得你得多练习
I think you need to practice
男生跟 女生的约会对白 在你出门前
your boy girl dating talk at home before you come out.
我可能练过
Yeah, I probably do.
我给你本书 若你那样有兴趣
I'll give you a book if you're that interested.
约会时
On dating?
喷血时
On blood.
还有个医学问题？可能
Another medical question perhaps?
没 我只觉得你是我见过的最漂亮的
No. I just think you're the prettiest thing I ever seen.
那是因为我四周黑麻麻地
That's because I'm sitting in the dark.
不
No,
你就是美丽
you're just beautiful.
让路
Out of the way!
你得看好路再走
You need to watch where you're going.
对不起 我没想到你会介意
I'm sorry. I didn't think you'd mind.
你没问过
You didn't ask.
- 我想你可能会喜欢 - 就算我喜欢 你也要先问
- I thought you might have liked it. - Well, I might have if you'd asked.
你来吗
You coming?
走路小心点
Watch where you're walking!
你为何对我们只字不提
Why didn't you say nothing to us?
因为你会试着让我说出来
'Cause you would have tried and talked me out of it,
- 亦知我做得对 - 那主的诫命呢
- and I know what I'm doing is right. - And what about His Commandment?
在战争中那不是杀戮
It's not killing in a war.
我是保护 许多从我们教会入伍的男孩
It's protecting. Loads of boys from our church are going.
- 嗯 - 战事已起 他们要人
- Yeah. - There is a war and they need men.
在造纸厂上班救不了国
And working in a paper mill ain't going to save this country.
看起来就像影星
Looks like a movie star,
孩子
our boy.
制服好看
Nice uniform,
帽子不错
good hat.
提醒了我 哈代穿这身制服是啥样
Reminds me of how Artie Giddens looked in his uniform
当我们奔赴法国
when we went to France.
还记得他吗？伯莎
Remember him, Bertha?
- 不要 汤姆 - 什么
- Don't, Tom. - What?
我只是说哈尔穿起制服看着如何时髦
I'm just saying how snappy Artie looked in his uniform.
而所有的女孩似乎都这么认为
All you girls certainly seemed to think so.
他使她们涌向他 他得意之极
He had them flocking to him. He was most proud.
我只希望哈尔中枪时
I just hope that when our Hal gets shot,
是前面中枪
it's through the front of his jacket.
干净利落 没痛苦
Like a simple entry wound, not much mess.
若是击中背部
Artie got hit in the back,
把他的肠子 从前面出来落得到处都是
it blew most of his guts and intestines out his front, offal everywhere.
彻底毁掉他的制服
Wrecked his uniform entirely.
很幸运 他死了
It was lucky he was dead,
所以他从不知他的制服看上去有多糟
so he never knew how awful his uniform looked.
离开我的视线
Get outta of my sight.
我说难道你是山羊吗？
What are you, part mountain goat?
你不帮我吗？德斯蒙德·多斯
Are you going to help me, Desmond Doss,
或者你只想让我困住
or are you just going to leave me stranded?
我会帮你的 但你得付出代价
I'll help you, but it's gonna cost you.
什么
What?
亲一个
A kiss.
- 这纯粹是敲诈 - 是的 女士
- That is pure blackmail. - Well, yes, ma'am, it is.
但那仍是我的条件
But that is still my condition.
是个交易
That's the deal.
我想抱着你亲
And I'm going to hold you to it.
等等
Well, hold on now.
你不会打我？是吗
You ain't gonna slap me, are you?
因我可能会带着你跟我掉下去
'Cause I fall off, I'm going to take you with me.
吻我即知
Kiss me and find out.
坎宁安实用解剖学手册
什么
What?
我得参军
I have to enlist.
我不能留在这儿而让他们都为我而战
I can't stay here while all of them go fight for me.
- 是的 你能 你能留在这儿 - 多萝西 我必须
- Yes, you can. You can stay here. - Dorothy, I have to.
我要当军医
I want to be a medic.
我指我是去救人而非杀人
I figure I'll be saving people, not killing them.
我得上班了 不想迟到
I have to go to work. I'm going to be late.
多萝西 别这样 多萝西 多萝西
Dorothy. Dorothy, darling. Dorothy. Dorothy!
那么你想求我嫁给你还是别的
So are you going to ask me to marry you or what?
我不知你会否还讨厌我
Well, I don't know. You still going to have me?
我也不知 你可没问
Well, I wouldn't know, you haven't asked.
那 我来问你
Well, I'm asking you,
全心全意地 你愿意嫁给我吗
with all my heart and then some. Will you marry me?
那当然
Then, yes.
是的 我愿意
Yes, I will.
何时
When?
待到你首次出征时
Soon as you get your first leave.
但我此刻仍不喜欢你
But I still don't like you at this moment.
对啊
Yeah.
- 好 - 好
- Okay. - Okay.
我爱你
Well, I love you.
嘘
Shh!
妈妈说在这儿能见到你
Momma said come see you here.
对
Yeah.
这三位是我最好的朋友
These three were my best friends.
我们一起长大
I grew up with 'em,
一起惹麻烦 一起追女生
I got into trouble with 'em, chased girls with 'em.
我们一起参军
And I enlisted with 'em.
然后吾友们长眠于此
Now my friends are there,
泥草覆身 虫蛆啃噬
covered in dirt and grass and eaten by worms.
我不想探望我孩子于此
I don't want to have to visit my sons here.
爸爸我已签约
Daddy, I signed up already.
我别无选择除了入伍 爸爸
I couldn't do otherwise, Pop.
- 人人都这样 - 你并非人人
- Everybody else is doing... - You ain't everybody else!
人人忙做事 不加思索 有如
Everybody else jumps in and does things quick, without thinking! Like the
我们这种该死的蠢货
Like the damn idiot fools we were.
你可知活着的士兵所以活着 只因他们能思考
And soldiers who live, they live because they can do that!
你不能
You can't!
你得坐下思考 凡事祷告
Look, you gotta sit and think and pray about everything.
看看你 你现在就想想
I mean, look at you, you're doing it right now.
你无法靠自己活着 如果你去
You won't be able to live with yourself if you go.
不 我无法靠自己活着 假如我不去
No, I won't be able to live with myself if I don't.
我要当个军医
I'm going to be a medic.
那将是我服役的方式
That's going to be my way to serve.
那你就去把它想清楚
See, there you go, thinking it all out.
你以为这场战争会让你称心如意
What, you figure this war is just going to fit in with you,
如你所愿
your ideas?
我只晓得我不怀疑这会很难
Well, I don't doubt it's going to be hard.
不是难 是不可能
It won't be hard, it'll be impossible.
无论如何 如今你那疯狂脑子里的信仰
You know, whatever beliefs you have in your crazy head now,
它们永不发生 不起作用
they won't ever play out. It don't work that way.
如有某些我所不知的奇遇 你活下来
And if by some, I don't know, miracle chance you survive,
你不会把感谢给上帝
you won't be giving no thanks to God.
- 休息？- 休息下
- Ready? - Ready.
我们该走了
Y'all need some air.
来吧 伙计们 迈迈腿 我理解
Come on, fellas, shake a leg. Uncle Sam's got you now.
你得跟老妈说再见
Say goodbye to Momma.
来吧
Come on.
女士们 请离开公共汽车
Ladies, please, step away from the bus.
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
- 我非得找根撬棍吗？- 拿着
- Do I need a crowbar? - Here.
我要你带上这个
I want you to have this.
是我的
It's mine.
你把它放在这儿
You keep it right here,
我就在那儿
where I'll be.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
我爱你
I love you.
回到我身边 德斯蒙德·多斯 我爱你
杰克逊堡
我非得盯着你的畸形吗？每次我走到床上
Do I have to gaze at your deformity every time I walk to my bed?
眼红吧 我的朋友
Gaze upon it in envy, my friend.
你还好吗
You okay there?
你好象迷了路
You look lost.
要不你就坐这儿
Vacancy right here.
不错的选择 那儿能从高山看到大湖
Wise choice. It's got views of the mountains down to the lake.
兰德尔·富勒
Randall Fuller.
德斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
叫他"教授" 你听不懂他说的每个字
Call him "Teach."
No one understands a word he says.
因为这儿没人懂
That's because no one else here can read.
那对睾丸的主人自称"好莱坞"
The testicles there belong to a man calling himself "Hollywood."
它们看起来更像是属于小家伙
They look like they belong to a smaller guy.
你懂睾丸
You know testicles.
哦 嘿 我刚买这双鞋
Oh! Hey, I just got these shoes.
嘿 呃 格雷斯·诺兰 来自雷德伍德 你呢
Hey, uh, Grease Nolan, outta Red Hook. Where you from?
- 弗吉尼亚 - 威尔·比利哈
- Virginia. - Ooh, hillbilly, huh?
你娶了你第一个表妹
You marry your first cousin?
开个玩笑
I'm just joking.
那边的史密提跟科恩斯基臭味相投
That's Smitty over there, whipping Kirzinski's ass.
好象你更牛？笨蛋
Like you were doing any better, chowder head.
嘿 我可不想使你丢脸
Hey, I didn't want to embarrass you.
沃尔·科恩斯基 很高兴见到你
Wal Kirzinski, nice to meet you.
嘿 竹竿 你说你名字是啥？
Hey, beanpole, what did you say your name was?
德斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
边上那位是德克萨斯·刘易斯 当他是某类牛仔
That's Tex Lewis over there, he thinks he's some kind of cowboy.
还有维托·雷诺利 他也许个小 但他可是斗牛犬
And, uh, Vito Rinnelli. He may be small, but he is a bulldog.
- 嗨 - 你好吗？
- Hey. - How you doing?
- 德斯蒙德 - 噢
- Desmond. - Yeah.
- 这位帅哥是幸运的福特 - 嘿
- This handsome guy right here is Lucky Ford. - Hey.
那边是沃克和皮尼克 他们自诩为洗牌手
That's Walker and Pinnick over there pretending they're card sharks.
安静 格雷斯 好吗
Pipe down, Grease, all right?
除非你想被钱塞住嘴
Unless you want to put your money where your mouth is.
噢 嘿
Oh, hey,
这书
the old
不错吧
good book, right?
我觉得是 我觉得鲁西也有本好书
I think... I think Lucky's got a good book.
是吧 鲁西
Right, Lucky?
是本好书
It's a good read.
立正
Attention!
列队 行动
Line up! Move it!
一起来 行动 行动
Let's go, move it. Move it.
你看起来很怪
You are a very strange-looking individual
你不介意我这样说吧？列兵
if you don't mind me saying so, Private.
- 姓名 - 安迪·沃克
- Name? - Andy Walker.
你死多久了？孩子
How long have you been dead, son?
长官 我不是长官
- Sir? - I am not "Sir"!
我是豪厄尔中士或军士
I am Sergeant Howell or Sarge.
"长官"是叫没用的人
"Sir" you save for useless people.
- 你的名字是"食尸鬼"你说呢 - 沃克 中士
- The name is "Ghoul," you say? - Walker, Sergeant!
- "食尸鬼"是 - 是的 中士
- Ghoul it is. - Yes, Sergeant!
你的看上去有失常态 列兵
There's something off in your presentation, Private.
很难说
Can't place it.
是你的头发
Is it your hair?
还是你裤子上的皱纹
Is it the wrinkle in your trousers?
我脚上插着刀 中士
I have a knife in my foot, Sergeant.
- 噢 是的 当然 是这把刀 - 不
- Oh, yes, of course, that's it. The knife. - No,
- 你叫什么名字？士兵 - 史密提·瑞克
- What is your name, soldier? - Smitty Ryker.
你的名字是"列兵白痴" 你可知为何
your name is Private Idiot. Do you know why?
- 因为我脚上插着刀 - 谁会把刀插在哪儿？列兵
- Because I have a knife in my foot. - Who placed the knife there, Private?
这是个意外 中士 我在练拉伸
It was an accident, Sarge. We was playing Stretch.
据我所知你不是有意插在那儿
I am heartened by the knowledge you did not place it there with intention.
谁扔的刀
Who threw the knife?
是我 中士 列兵科恩斯基
I did, Sergeant. Private Kirzinski.
你是印地安部族 你属哪个部落？孩子
You look part Indian. To what tribe do you belong, son?
- 不 我是波兰人 - 错
- No, I'm Polish. - Wrong.
我相信你一定有切诺基族或肖尼族血统
I believe you must have Cherokee or Shawnee blood in you.
- 不 长官 - 你在反驳我
- No, Sergeant. - Are you contradicting me,
- 你这兔崽子 - 不 中士
- you wagon-burning son of a bitch? - No, Sergeant!
让我见识下你的印第安战嚎孩子
Let me see your Indian war cry, son.
我不会
I don't...
大声些 让我看看
Louder! Let me see it.
你的动物图腾是啥
What is your animal spirit?
你是乌梢蛇？
Are you a garter snake?
- 不 中士 - 你是花栗鼠？
- No, Sergeant! - Are you a chipmunk?
- 不 中士 - 你是跳舞的驯鹿？
- No, Sergeant! - Are you a dancing reindeer?
- 不 中士 - 你在反驳我 中士？
- No, Sergeant! - Are you contradicting me, Private?
- 不 中士 - 好
- No, Sergeant! - Good.
那我从此叫你"酋长"
Then I shall henceforth call you "Chief"
作为向你族人致以崇高敬意的标识
as a sign of great respect to your people.
谢谢你 中士
Thank you, Sergeant!
你在咧嘴笑我孩子？还是你经常这样
Are you grinning at me, boy, or is that your natural state?
不 中士
No, Sergeant.
- 姓名 列兵 - 德斯蒙德·多斯
- Name, Private? - Desmond Doss.
我见过的玉米杆都都比你强得多
I have seen stalks of corn with better physiques.
搞得我想扯掉你的耳朵 列兵
Makes me want to pull an ear off, Private.
- 你能扛人吗？- 是 中士
- Can you carry your weight? - Yes, Sergeant!
可不是你这种重量的
Should be easy for you, then.
- 下士 - 中士
- Corporal. - Sergeant.
你要确保此人别被大风刮走
Make sure you keep this man away from strong winds.
是 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
列兵"白痴"
Private Idiot.
- 是 中士 - 把脚抬高
- Yes, Sergeant. - Raise your foot.
抬高点
Higher.
全部出去 马上
Everyone outside. Now!
动起来
Move it.
我说了动起来
I said move it.
我得穿制服 中士
All right. Just getting in my uniform, Sarge.
- 我有叫他穿吗？下士 - 没有 中士
- Did I ask him to, Corporal? - No memory of it, Sarge.
我相信任何为自己自然裸露而如此骄傲的男人
I believe any man who takes such pride in his natural naked state
肯定会享受户外的清爽
will surely enjoy the brisk of the outdoors.
现在放开你的私处 列兵帕兹
Now move your privates, Private Parts!
行动
Move it!
行动 你这个裸露崽子
You son of an exhibitionist!
我要教你们怎么结单套
I am going to teach you how to tie a bowline knot,
这样你们能够把你的懒屁股从高处放下
so you can get your sorry asses down from a height,
好让我能踢它们
so I may then kick them!
绕成一个圈
Create a loop.
这是兔子窝
This is the rabbit hole.
兔子出了窝 绕着树子跑
The rabbit comes out of his hole, runs around the tree,
回到兔子窝
goes back into the hole.
完成
All right,
一起做
let's go!
很好德克萨斯
Very good, Tex.
继续努力 "教授"
Keep struggling, Teach.
你从没套过山羊吗 "好莱坞"
Have you ever roped a goat, Hollywood?
没有军士
No, Sarge.
你从没瞪过山羊眼？
Have you ever looked into a goat's eyes?
- 没有 中士 - 好 那才不正常
- No, Sarge. - Good, that would be unnatural.
你懂如不吸气必得死
You know if you don't breathe, you'll die.
不错 列兵"白痴"
Good, Private Idiot.
恭喜你老油条 你刚掉了五十英尺 摔断了脖子
Congratulations, Greaseball, you just fell 50 feet and broke your neck!
棒极了
Brilliant,
列兵维托·雷诺利
Private Vito Rinnelli.
你勒死自己毫无怜悯
You strangled yourself, numb nuts!
你是贝内利的粉丝
Are you a fan of Benito?
- 不是 中士 - 有一点
- No, Sergeant. - A bit taller.
你是美国人 你会更高些
If you were American, you'd be taller.
这是什么 多斯
What've we got here, Doss,
每个乳房各一个
one for each titty?
你是结单套 孩子
You were tying a bowline, boy,
不是结胸罩
not building a bra!
- 有何可笑 下士？- 说不出来 中士
- What is so funny, Corporal? - Couldn't tell you, Sergeant.
来吧 来吧 娘们 爬起来 快 快
Come on! Come on, ladies, pick it up! Move it! Move it!
给我燃起来 快点
I want to see some fire here. A little hustle.
给我露几手
Show me something!
拼命跑
Run like you mean it!
- 下 下 下 更快 更快 更快 - 快 跑 跑
- Down, down, down! Faster, faster! - Come on. Move it! Move it!
一起去清洗地道 男孩们
Let's go, it's bath time, boys!
现在是时候洗洗了
It's bath time! trust you now.
向前 向前 向前
Move! Move! Move!
我想看到你赢 一起来
I want to see you work. Let's go!
钻 钻 钻
Dig, dig, dig!
不要忘记耳后有人 一起来 快
Don't forget behind your ears. Let's go. Move!
我敢打赌你正享受这样 裸露狂
I bet you're enjoying this, you naked degenerate.
一起来 快点 快点 快点 动起来
Let's go! Hustle. Hustle. Hustle. Move!
一起来 还等啥 一起来 把屁股搬起来
Let's go! What are we waiting on? Let's go! Move your ass!
爬木头 翻墙壁 别跟废物亲近
Get the wood! Get the wall! Don't get splinters!
加油
Drive!
天啊 你没事吧？
Jeez, are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
- 打起精神来 小伙子们 走 - 快 走
- Some spirit here, boys. Move! - Come on, move!
你到底啥毛病？不准休息
What the hell is wrong with you? No one said take a rest!
把屁股搬到终点线 快跑 快跑
Move your asses to the finish line! Move! Move!
快点 快点
Hustle! Hustle!
让你的屁股跨过该死的线
Get your asses across that line!
啊 干得漂亮 多斯
Time! Nice work, Doss!
这是美国政府给你们
This is a personal gift from the United States government
每一位的个人礼物
to each and every one of you.
标准美式步枪 30口径 M1 加兰德步枪
A standard issue U.S. rifle, caliber .30, M1,
单配弹夹 肩射式半自动武器
a clip-fed, shoulder-fired, semi-automatic weapon
用于把死亡同毁灭带给敌人
designed to bring death and destruction to the enemy.
它将成为你的爱侣
This is to be your lover,
你的情人
your mistress
你的小妾
your concubine.
也许是
Perhaps
也许是 你生命中唯一的真爱
the only thing in life you will ever truly love.
伙计们 一起来跳舞
Fellas, let's dance.
挑个女孩
Grab a girl.
不要把枪对着前方
Don't point your gun forward.
我今天不想中弹
I do not want to be shot today.
不管你多么心痒
No matter how much you are tempted.
把枪放侧边
Place the weapon by your side.
立正
Pay attention.
有问题吗 列兵"玉米杆"
Problem, Private Corn Stalk?
尺寸不对
Is there not one in your size,
还是颜色有问题
or is it the color that is the issue?
不 中士
No, Sarge.
我被告知我不必携带武器
I was... I was told I don't have to carry a weapon.
上前一步列兵 我没听清
Come again? Step forward, Private. I can't be hearing this right.
我很抱歉 中士
Well, I'm sorry, Sergeant.
我不能碰枪
I can't touch a gun.
究竟是什么问题
What exactly is the problem?
没有问题 只是误会
No problem, just a mistake, sir.
我参军时就说过 这不可能
I told the Army when I joined up. That's not possible.
你可知为何不可能 列兵
Do you know why it's not possible, Private?
不 长官
No, sir.
因为美军不会犯错
Because the United States Army does not make mistakes.
若有问题
So if there's a problem, .
若有问题 你就是那问题
you must be that problem.
我从没想过被派到步兵连
I was just never supposed to be sent to a rifle company.
他是个"CO" 长官
He's a C.O., sir.
你是个"拒服兵役者"
You're a conscientious objector,
而你参了军
and you joined the Army?
不 先生
Well, no, sir,
我是个"尽责的合作者"
I'm a conscientious cooperator.
- 你在愚弄我？多斯 - 不 不 先生 我自愿
- Are you screwing with me, Doss? - No. No, sir. I volunteered.
我穿制服没问题
I ain't got no problem with wearing my uniform,
向国旗行礼 尽我的义务
or saluting the flag and doing my duty.
只是
It's just
只是不可以拿枪杀人
just carrying a gun and the taking of human life.
你不杀人？
You don't kill?
- 就这些 - 是的 先生 就这些
- That's all. - Yes, sir, that's all.
你知战争中杀戮确实很多
You know quite a bit of killing does occur in a war?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我是说 战争的本质
I mean, that is the essential nature of war.
是 长官
Yes, sir. .
好吧
All right.
你对美军还有任何其它要求吗
Do you have any other requirements of the United States Army?
还有什么我们可以做 以确保
Is there anything else that we can do to ensure
你会满意地跟我们一起呆这儿
that you have a comfortable stay here with us?
他不想在周六工作 长官
He doesn't want to work on Saturdays, sir.
嗯 周六是
Well, Saturdays...
我是"基督复临安息日"者 因此
I'm a Seventh-day Adventist. So,
周六是我的安息日 那就不允许我工作
Saturday is my Sabbath, so I'm not allowed to work then.
我不认为这会带来问题 你呢？中士
I don't think that poses a problem, do you, Sergeant?
我们应要求敌人别在安息日进攻
We shall simply ask the enemy not to invade on the Sabbath,
因为列兵多斯在此祈祷
'cause Private Doss here is at prayer.
好吧
All right.
现在我们搞清楚了
Now we got that clear.
现在让我告诉你我的要求 它们不像
Now let me tell you my requirements.
你的那么复杂 它们极简单
They're not as complicated as yours. They're very simple.
只要你一直呆在这个连队里 由我指挥
As long as you're in this company, under my command,
你就得服从我的命令 句号
you will obey my orders. Period.
你若在此做不到 我不信你在战斗能做到
If you can't do it here, I can't trust you to do it in battle.
我会把你视为符合"第八条例"
I'm putting you in for a Section 8,
美军二战条例第八条 判断军人精神方面是否适合服役
"我会让你免役
psychiatric discharge.
解散
Dismissed.
先生们
Gentlemen!
我想让你们见见列兵德斯蒙德·多斯
I want you to meet Private Desmond Doss.
显然地
Apparently,
显然地 列兵多斯不相信暴力
Private Doss does not believe in violence.
他不愿实施暴力
He does not practice violence.
他甚至不屑摸枪
He will not even deign to touch a weapon.
要知道 列兵多斯
You see, Private Doss
是一个"拒服兵役者"
is a conscientious objector.
所以我恳请你们
So I plead with you,
别指望他在战场上拯救你
do not look to him to save you on the battlefield,
因为他无疑会
because he will undoubtedly
太忙于跟他的良心搏斗
be too busy wrestling with his conscience
去协助
to assist.
- 中士 那不是真的 中士 - 列兵 别解释了
- Sarge, that's not true. - Private, as you were.
我知道你们中有些人对此很有意见
Now, I realize some of you might have strong feelings about this.
那就是男人为何而战
It is what we men fight for.
为了捍卫权利
To defend our rights,
为了保护妇女和儿童
and to protect our women and children.
即使列兵多斯的信念
Even if Private Doss' beliefs
可能会导致妇女和儿童死亡
might cause women and children to die.
所以我希望本连队的每个人
So I will expect everyone in this company
给予列兵多斯 充分尊重他应有的尊重
to give Private Doss the full measure of respect he is due
因为短时间内 他将与我们同在
for the short time he will be with us.
清楚了吗
Am I clear?
是的 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
你拿的是啥 多斯
What'cha got there, Dessie?
你知道那是什么吗？像是袖珍版
You know what that is. It just seems kind of small.
专门给不完整的男人吧
It's half the Bible for half the man.
看彼得份上 史密提 把圣经还给他
For Pete's sake, Smitty, give him back his Bible.
我没跟你说
I don't remember speaking to you.
你为何不打架
So, how come you don't fight?
你自以为比我们优秀
You think you're better than us?
不
No.
那么 如果你被攻击 怎么办
What if you was attacked?
喜欢吗
Say, like that.
圣经说 你要转过另一边脸
The Bible says to turn the other cheek, don't it?
看见没？跟信仰无关 伙计们
See, I don't think this is a question of religion, fellas.
我认为是懦弱
I think this is cowardice,
显而易见
plain and simple.
你没事吧 多斯？
Is that right, Doss?
你娘炮？是吗
Are you chickenshit, that it?
来啊
Go on,
来打
take a poke.
那好 我不还手
Tell you what, I'm going to give you a free shot.
就是那儿
Right there.
打我 多斯
Hit me, Doss.
来
Go on.
- 啥毛病 - 上啊
- Let him have it. - Go ahead.
不打？
No?
娘炮
Chickenshit.
等等 这是什么？
Hold on here. What is this?
把它给我
Give me that.
- 这娘们好看 - 漂亮
- This is a fine-looking broad. - Nice.
嘿 让大伙看一下
Hey, pass it around.
如今这种娘们
Now, this would be the kind of broad
真正的男人才配得上
that deserves a real man.
把它还给我
Give me that back.
请
Please.
请把它归还 史密提
"Please give it back, Smitty."
Please give it back, Smitty.
你听得到声音？德斯蒙德
Do you hear voices, Desmond?
不 长官
No, sir.
我理解为上帝在跟你说话？是那样吗
But I understand that God talks to you. Is that right?
长官 我没疯
Sir, I'm not a crazy person.
那你觉得大多数人怎么看你
Is that how you feel most people regard you,
疯子
a crazy person?
我不同别人我知道 只是
I'm different. I know that, but...
我不愿弄虚作假
I'm not going to pretend to be something I'm not.
我就是我
I am what I am.
听起来很孤独
Sounds lonely.
你孤独吗
You lonely?
- 那么 你听不到声音 -不 长官
- So, you don't hear voices. - No, sir.
我向上帝祷告
I pray to God
我还觉得他能听见 只是那并非交谈
and I like to think He hears me, but it ain't a conversation,
就像此刻我绝不会假装我们得谈谈
like the one we're pretending to have right now.
- 假装？列兵 - 是 长官
- Pretending, Private? - Well, yes, sir.
我知道你的打算干嘛 说我是"第八条例者"
I know all you really want to do is give me a Section 8,
把我撵出部队 只是
drum me out of the Army, but
我不是
I'm not off
神明在上
up above.
我只是信我所信
I just simply believe what I believe.
好吧 我尽量去理解
Well, I'm trying to understand,
好吗？
all right?
是上帝叫你别拿枪
Was it God who told you not to pick up a rifle?
上帝说勿杀人
God says not to kill.
那是他的最重要的戒律之一
That's one of His most important Commandments.
大多数人把此理解为别谋杀
Most people take that to mean, "Don't commit murder."
战争是完全不同的情况
War is a completely different set of circumstances.
耶稣说
Jesus said,
我把一个新的命令给你们
"A new Commandment I give unto you,
即你爱别人 有如我爱你
that you love one another, just as I have loved you."
我们正在跟撒旦作战
This is Satan himself we're fighting.
肯定是
Surely,
虔诚的基督徒 你看得出来
as a good Christian, you can see that.
我看得出 长官 这也是我参军的原因
I can see that, sir, and that is why I joined up.
但是很抱歉 我不能带武器
But I'm sorry, I will not bear arms.
他的宗教观确实独一无二 但这些
His religious views are certainly unique,
不违反第八条例的免役范畴
but they do not constitute grounds for a Section 8 discharge.
我该如何让这样的人听命于我
How am I supposed to maintain discipline with a man like that in my unit?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他是一个合法的"拒服兵役者"
But he is a legitimate conscientious objector,
他必须被允许作为"军医"提供
and he must be allowed to work as a combat medic,
他有资格在所有其它区域进行训练
provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training.
也许我们可帮助缓和他的想法
Perhaps we could help make believe in his idea.
好 你把他关在兵营去KP
Yeah, you restrict him to barracks and KP.
他扔上帝给你 你扔地狱砸他
If he throws God at you, you throw hell right at him.
我要他消失
I want him gone.
多斯
Doss, your area is a disgrace.
这是个猪圈
It's a pig sty!
- 有何可笑 瑞克？- 不 中士
- Something funny, Ryker? - No, Sarge!
- 你脑子进大粪了？- 不 中士
- You got some shit on your mind? - No, Sarge!
你们没意识到的
What you men fail to recognize
就是一只队伍并不会比它的最弱者更强
is a unit is no better than its weakest member!
我希望你们记住这教训
Now, to help you learn that lesson,
本周末不准休息
there will be no passes this weekend.
全部去KP
You will all be on KP!
现在全体全速徒步20英里
Right now, everybody in full gear for a 20-mile hike.
一起去 一起去
Let's go! Let's go.
保持头脑清醒
Get your heads right.
不要自怜
Don't start feeling sorry for yourself.
你们的自怜样叫我恶心
Makes me sick see you feel sorry for yourself.
你们这些狗不知累为何物
You dogs don't know what tired is.
我们会继续跑直到我倒下
We're going to keep going till I drop.
来吧 伙计们
Come on guys.
嘿 住手 别打了 去睡觉
Hey, knock it off. Trying to sleep here.
- 离我远点 滚开 - 好 好
- Get off me. Get off me. - Okay. All right.
为什么你还在这里
Why the hell are you still here?
- 立正 - 原地别动
- Attention - As you were.
多斯在哪儿
Where's Doss?
这对你不好 伙计
This isn't good for anybody.
当然 我参军不是想这样
Sure ain't what I joined up for.
这跟你为何参军无关
It's not about what you joined up for.
有关在此诸位的命
It's about the lives of every man in here.
及你的命 孩子
And yours, son.
是时候退出了
It's time to quit this.
穿好衣服 我送你
Finish getting dressed and I'll walk you down.
好了 多斯
It's okay, Doss.
别为此羞愧
There's no shame in this.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我有额外的执勤 今天 上午我得去KP 所以
I got extra guard duty today, and I'm on KP this morning, so...
我不能
Can't.
好吧 多斯
All right, Doss.
列兵多斯
Private Doss,
你能认出打你的人吗
can you identify the men that beat you?
不 中士
No, Sarge.
你是说你不知道是谁打了你
Are you saying that you don't know who attacked you?
我从未说过我被打了 中士
I never said I was attacked, Sarge.
你究竟在说啥？多斯
Well, what the hell are you saying, Doss?
你伤得难以入睡
You bruised half your body sleeping?
我睡得很沉
I... I sleep pretty hard.
好吧
Alright.
本周计划湿训 确保你戴上帽子
If you plan on getting wet this weekend, make sure you put on a hat.
下一个
Next.
我不希望任何人回来尿在奶油里
Don't want anyone coming back pissing cream.
你不是想要咖啡吗？中士
What, you don't want none for your coffee, Sarge?
给你颗枪子儿如何？史密提
How about a shot right now, Smitty?
- 讲讲经验 中士 - 下一个
- You speaking from experience, Sarge? - Next.
你得问你娘 老油条
You'd have to ask your mom about that, Greaseball.
稍息
At ease.
列兵多斯
Private Doss,
恐怕我不能准你的假
I'm afraid I can't authorize your pass.
假期只给通过基本训练的人
This is a furlough for men who have passed the basic training.
尊敬的长官 我过了
Well, sir, respectfully, sir, I have.
我申请了此假 三周前 我要结婚
I put in for this furlough three weeks ago. I'm getting married
今天下午
this afternoon.
你步枪不合格
It says you're not rifle qualified.
我不需要携带步枪 长官 上校施特尔策 他
Well, I'm not required to carry a rifle, sir. Colonel Stelzer, he...
上校施特尔策规定：
Colonel Stelzer's determination was...
特许多斯作为军医服役
"Doss must be allowed to work as a combat medic,
准予他有资格在任何其它区域完成训练
provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training."
而你在枪械上无资格 列兵
And you have not qualified on the rifle range, Private.
很清楚
Pretty clear.
给我演示下你会拿枪
Show me you know how to handle a rifle
我就准假
and I'll sign your furlough.
- 下士坎农 - 长官
- Corporal Cannon. - Sir!
给列兵多斯你的枪
Hand Private Doss your firearm.
- 我不会碰步枪 长官- 我不是要求你 列兵
- I won't touch a rifle, sir. - I'm not asking you, Private!
这是个部队指挥官的直接命令
That is a direct order from a company commander.
看上帝份上 多斯
For God's sake, Doss,
别再废话 退出
you stop this nonsense and quit.
拒绝
Refuse,
我则没有追索权 只能送你去军事法庭
and I will have no recourse but to court-martial you,
你将在军事监狱度过战争期
and you will spend the duration of the war in a military prison.
我不能 长官
I can't, sir.
你愿意等多久 多萝西
How much longer would you like to wait, Dorothy?
我想得足够久
I think it's been long enough.
这真是太遗憾了
I'm so very sorry.
有时男人会临阵退缩
Sometimes men just get cold feet.
有的男人会有
Some men might.
但我的德斯蒙德不会
Not my Desmond.
你可能觉得我真是个混蛋
You probably think I'm a real son of a bitch
只在乎规定不关心自己人
who cares only about regulations and not his men.
可以吗
May I?
我跟任何人一样信任此书
I believe in this book as much as any man.
跟任何人一样
And just like any man,
我会被良心困扰
I wrestle with my conscience,
但当世上你珍视的一切皆受摧残 你会怎做？
but what do you do when everything you value in this world is under attack?
我不知道 长官
I don't know, sir.
我没法回答那种深刻的问题
I ain't got answers to questions that big,
但我感同我价值观也在饱受摧残
but I also feel like my values are under attack,
我不知何故
and I don't know why.
我不关心你的原则 因为日本人不在乎
I don't give a rat's ass about your principles because the Japs don't.
如果日本女人攻击你
If one of them attacks you and
受伤的士兵 你怎么办
some wounded soldier, what are you gonna do?
用你的圣经揍他
Hit him with your Bible?
我已准备好为大家牺牲
I'm prepared to give my life for my men.
你无法赢得战争即使你牺牲
You don't win wars by giving up your life.
看吧
Look,
看吧 我只身到此 因我不愿看到你烂在牢房
I'm only here because I don't want to see you rotting in a prison cell.
认罪 为自己争取法庭怜悯
Plead guilty, throw yourself at the mercy of the court.
也许他们会让你回家祈祷
Maybe they'll let you go home and pray.
让勇士们去赢得战争
Let the brave men out there go and win this war.
如果我不能说服你
If I can't convince you,
也许她可以
maybe she can.
他们不准我打电话你
They wouldn't let me call you.
我知道不是你不打
I knew it wasn't your making.
他们对你做了些啥
What have they done to you?
没关系 我很好
It's okay, I'm all right.
只是打了几下墙还有些失落
I just went a couple of rounds with the wall and lost.
他们说你会入狱 德斯蒙德
They're saying you could go to prison, Desmond.
甚至更糟
Leavenworth.
一定有别的办法
There must be some other way.
我不知将会怎样
I don't know what that could be.
我做了他们要求的每件事 除了这件事
I've done everything they asked me, except this one thing,
他们一直待我如罪犯 只因我不愿杀敌
and I'm being treated like a criminal just 'cause I won't kill.
你尽了力
You tried.
没人否认
Nobody can say you didn't.
但你在狱中能救谁
But who are you going to save in prison?
可能没人
Probably nobody.
那你为何不拿起笨枪 四处挥挥
Then why can't you just pick up the stupid gun and wave it around?
你不必用枪 只需带枪
You don't have to use it, just meet them halfway.
- 我不能那样做 - 是的 你能 这只是骄傲
- I can't do that. - Yes, you can. It's just pride.
骄傲跟倔强 别把你的意志跟上帝的混同
Pride and stubbornness. Don't confuse your will with the Lord's.
我一直很骄傲
Have I been prideful?
也许我真的很骄傲
Maybe I am prideful.
但我不知 我怎能独自活着
But I don't know how I'm going to live with myself
若不忠于我之所信
if I don't stay true to what I believe.
看着我们你怎能跟我一起活下去
Much less how you could live with me.
我想做个男人 如你所见
I'd never be the man that I want to be in your eyes.
我爱上你
I fell in love with you
因你不象其他人
because you weren't like anyone else
你也不会想那样
and you didn't try to be.
任何时刻都别认为你会让我失望
Do not think for one moment that you will disappoint me.
我将爱你
I will love you
无论怎样
no matter what.
我不知他要做啥
I don't know what he's gonna do.
他输定了 无论如何
He loses no matter what.
他们想让他认罪
They want him to plead guilty,
但这会让他开除军籍
but then he'll get a dishonorable discharge.
否则他就是违抗他们 他必会入狱
Otherwise he fights them, and he for sure goes to prison.
无论怎样 他们会叫他懦夫
Either way, they'll call him a coward
我看不出他怎能那样活着
and I don't see how he can live with that.
谢谢你 多萝西
Well, thank you, Dorothy.
如果你能跟他谈谈
If you get to talk to him,
告诉他我们爱他 会为他祈祷
tell him that we love him and that we're praying for him.
会为你们祈祷
We're praying for both of you.
我会的
I will.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
汤姆 你疯了 你神志不清了
Tom, you're out of your mind, you're delirious.
我当然失去了理智
Of course, I'm out of my mind.
你以为我是谁 我疯了
What do you think I am? I'm out of my mind.
请你离开这屋
You leave this room.
不要 汤姆 把它放下
No, Tom! Put it down!
- 放开我 婆娘 - 嘿
- Get away from me, woman! - Hey!
有何贵干 先生
May I help you, sir?
我想找准将穆斯格罗夫
I wish to speak to Brigadier General Musgrove.
没有预约可不行 那样绝无可能
Not without an appointment you can't. That would be quite impossible.
如能劳你告诉他：
Uh, if you would kindly tell him
下士托马斯·多斯将感激一个简短的面谈
Corporal Thomas Doss would appreciate a brief word.
他在开非常重要的会
He's in a very important meeting.
我跟他在法国贝洛伍德打过仗 他是我队长
I fought with him in France at Belleau Wood. He was my captain.
求您女士 此事至关重要
Please, ma'am, it's most vital.
谢谢 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
门外有个人 托马斯·多斯
There's a man out there, Tom Doss.
多斯？
Doss?
仅需一分钟
Be over in a minute.
你将安全到家 就跟没事一样
You'll be home safe and sound, like nothing ever happened.
这是列兵多斯的听证会
This is a hearing into the matter of Private Desmond Doss.
指控是他违反了其指挥官的
The charge is disobeying a series of direct orders
一系列直接命令 被告怎么说
from his commanding officer. How says the defendant?
列兵多斯希望进行无罪答辩
Private Doss wishes to enter a "not guilty" plea.
是这样吗 列兵？我以为已同意过
Is that so, Private? I thought this was agreed.
你想进行某种讨价还价的答辩？
You wanted to enter some sort of plea bargain.
- 是的 长官 但我改变了主意 - 就这样？
- Yes, sir, but I changed my mind. - Just like that?
你希望进行军事诉讼
You wish to proceed to a court-martial?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
那你如愿了列兵
Well, on your head, then, Private.
开始
Proceed.
法官大人
Your Honor,
列兵多斯挥舞其道德观
Private Doss waves his morality at us
有如某种荣誉的徽章
like it's some kind of badge of honor.
他炫耀他的蔑视 直接违反其指挥官的
He flaunts his contempt by directly disobeying a series of direct orders
一系列直接命令
from his commanding officer.
当这些最优秀的年轻人牺牲自己性命抵御邪恶时
When the very best of our young men are sacrificing their lives against...
- 你没事吧？- 是的
- You okay? - Yes.
- 他们还在审议？- 是的 先生
- Are they still deliberating? - Yes, sir.
好吧 你把这个拿进去
Okay, now you go take this in there.
我不能 必须是军人
I can't. It's strictly military personnel.
- 那你让他们中某个带进去 - 他们不会帮忙
- Well, then you get one of them to take it in. - They ain't out to help.
他们就等着埋了他
They're fixing to bury him.
任何军事法院只需问被告一个问题：
There is only one question that any military court need ask of the accused.
你否认违反上校萨斯顿的直接命令
Do you deny disobeying Colonel Sangston's direct orders?
那么 你否认吗？列兵
Well, do you, Private?
- 不 长官 我不否认 - 那你为何要质疑它呢
- No, sir. I don't. - Why are you contesting it, then?
这对你为何如此重要 使你拒绝去 触摸武器
Why is it so important to you, given your refusal to even touch a weapon,
即使是在部队中服役
to serve in a combat unit?
因为当日本偷袭珍珠港之时 我视为针对我个人
Because when the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor, I took it personal.
我认识的每个人都愤然参军 包括我
Everyone I knew was on fire to join up, including me.
有两个人在我们镇上
There were two men in my home town...
4-F 二战服役有关的物理 心理 或道德标准
被判4F不合格
declared 4-F unfit.
他们就自杀了 因为不能服役
They killed themselves because they couldn't serve.
为何？我在国防工厂有份工作 我可以续约
I had a job in a defense plant and I could've taken a deferment,
但那样不对
but that ain't right.
这样不对：别人就该去战斗去牺牲
It isn't right that other men should fight and die,
而我只是安全的呆坐屋里
that I would just be sitting at home safe.
我需要服役
I need to serve.
我有能力有激情作为军医服役
I got the energy and the passion to serve as a medic.
应当在其他伙伴当中 毫无危害 只是
Right in the middle with the other guys. No less danger, just...
当每个人都在取命 我是去救命
While everybody else is taking life, I'm going to be saving it.
既然这世界已把自己搞得四分五裂
With the world so set on tearing itself apart,
这对我不算是太糟糕的事
it doesn't seem like such a bad thing to me
去把那些碎片重聚一块儿
to want to put a little bit of it back together.
嗯
Hmm.
抱歉先生 无人准进
Sorry, sir, nobody's allowed to go...
不 你不知 我儿就是被告
No, you don't understand. My son is the defendant.
- 我理解 先生 但是无人准进 - 我有封信
- I understand, sir, but nobody's allowed... - I have information
- 非常重要 - 先生 你不可以进去
- that's important. - Sir, you are not allowed...
好吧 表达的情感值得称赞
While the sentiments expressed are laudable,
指控的事实无可争辩
the facts of the charge seem incontestable, so...
那边所为何事
What the hell is going on out there?
让他进来
Let him go.
- 那是一战制服 - 是的 长官
- That's a Great War uniform. - It is, sir.
长官 我得请您过目此信 恕我直言
Sir, I need to show you this. With respect, sir,
先生 您不再是军人
you are no longer a member of the military.
你不能参加此审议 我很遗憾
You are unable to attend this hearing. I'm sorry.
这么说真是这样的了
Is that truly the way it works, sir?
你为国而战 你失去了无数挚爱
You fight for your country, you lose so much that was dear to you,
然后你就没用了
and then you're done with?
没人认得你的制服了 所以无权发声
The uniform is forgotten. You have no voice.
你参战了里昂战役？
You were at Lys?
是的 长官 在贝洛森林
I was, sir. And at Belleau Wood.
两次授勋 我看到的 先生
Twice decorated, I see. Yes, sir.
我想你是被告之父
I take it you are the Private's father.
我是 长官 托马斯·多斯
I am, sir. Thomas Doss.
那么作为前军人 你知这儿有法律
Then, as a former military man, you know there are laws here...
长官 我清楚法律 我是 我知我儿受这些法律保护
Sir, I know the law and I know my son is protected by those laws.
它们受宪法约束
They are framed in our constitution.
我相信它们 像他那样
And I believe in them, as he does.
那就是为何我曾为捍卫它们而战
They are why I went and fought to protect them.
这就是我所思所为
At least, that is what I thought I was doing.
因为如果不是为此
Because if it wasn't for that,
我就不知我到底去那里干了啥 长官
then I have no idea what the hell I was doing there, sir.
谢谢你 下士多斯
Thank you, Corporal Doss.
让我看看这信
Let me have the letter.
你得离开
You must go.
被告作为一个"拒服兵役者"的权利
"The defendant's rights as a conscientious objector
受国会一项法案的保护
are protected by an Act of Congress
他不能被迫放弃这些权利
and he cannot be compelled to waive those rights.
权利包括本案述及之违抗携带武器命令
That includes, in this case, his disobeying orders to bear arms."
签署 准将穆斯格罗夫
Signed, Brigadier General Musgrove,
战争服务指挥官 华盛顿特区
War Services Commander, Washington, D.C.
上校
Colonel?
- 我撤销控诉 - 那么本案驳回
- I withdraw the charges, sir. - Then this case is dismissed.
列兵多斯 你可自由的投入战斗的地狱烈火
Private Doss, you are free to run into the hellfire of battle
无需任何武器保护自己
without a single weapon to protect yourself.
你可恢复原职责
You may resume your duties
作为军医开始训练
and begin training as a combat medic.
- 他去哪儿了？- 走了 出来就走
- Where is he? - Gone. Straight after.
- 我请求他留下 说他同样想留下 - 好 我明白
- I begged him to stay. I told him you'd want to see him. - No, I understand.
- 你回家后告诉他：我爱他 - 好的
- When you get home, you tell him I love him. - Okay.
好的
Okay.
你要好好的回到我身边
You better come home to me.
冲绳岛 三月 1945
山姆大叔微微笑
Uncle Sam is mild
平静有如孩子般
He's peaceful as a child
但是切忌让他闹
But never get him riled or you'll be whipped
好莱坞 闭嘴
Hollywood, shut up.
拜托 安静下
Come on, pipe down.
- 闭嘴 衰人 - 闭嘴
- Shut up, man. - Shut up!
我向上帝发誓 好莱坞 我要给你一枪
I swear to God, Hollywood, I will shoot you.
别唱了 可以吗 当我们到那儿时再唱
Put a sock in it, will you? Save the crowing for when we get there.
娱乐一下而已
Killjoy was here.
让路
Give him room.
小心 小心 靠边
Clear! Clear! Move aside!
美国陆军第96步兵师
The 96th...
他们都剩下些啥？
or what's left of them.
这些是他们的后备军
These are the guys we're replacing.
- 我觉得不错 - 安全
- Seems good to me. - Clear.
- 这儿挺好 - 安全
- As gold. - Clear.
安全 中士
All clear, Sarge!
上尉格洛弗
Captain Glover.
中尉曼维 96师
Lieutenant Manville, 96th.
我们被派给您 长官
We've been assigned to you, sir.
好的
Okay.
- 大家给这些伙计弄点吃的 - 是 长官
- Let's get these men some chow. - Yes, sir.
这是中士豪厄尔
This is, uh, Sergeant Howell.
- 很高兴见到你 长官 - 坐下
- Good to meet you, sir. - Sit down.
谁是多斯
Who's Doss?
在那儿
Over there.
你是多斯
You Doss?
伊夫·谢克特
Irv Schecter.
你和我和佩吉在此
You, and me and Page here
是本区仅有的医护人员 所以
are about the only medics we got left in this area. So,
我想我们将一起工作
I guess we're gonna be working together.
你刚从前线来
You just come off the line?
情形如何
What's it like?
我问了情形如何
I said, What's it like?
钢锯岭吗
Hacksaw.
我们攻下六次
We climbed up six times.
我 六次被他们赶出
Six times, they threw us off.
最后一次 基本上是全军覆没了
Last time, there wasn't anything left of the 96th.
他们是畜生
They're animals.
恶臭的畜生
Stinking animals.
小日本不关心他们是死是活
Nips don't care if they live or die.
他们想死 他们不断袭击你
They want to die. They keep coming at you.
他们从不放弃
And they ain't never going to give up.
永不
Never.
嘿 嘿 伙计
Here. Hey, buddy.
日本鬼专门袭击伤员
The Japs deliberately target the wounded.
去掉你所有的红十字标志
Lose all your Red Cross markings.
小日本极好枪击军医
Nips put a premium on shooting medics.
那白色的靶心
The white is a bull's-eye.
拿去 我给你个新头盔
Here, I got you a new helmet.
是均码的
One size fits all.
这是我们的目标
That's our objective.
钢锯岭
Hacksaw Ridge.
我们占领它
We take it,
可能就拿下冲绳
maybe we get Okinawa.
拿下冲绳 我们就能占领日本
We get Okinawa, we take Japan.
吸口气
Take a breather.
我们的海军朋友会温柔的请他们欢迎各位
Our pals in the Navy are going to soften them up for us.
那死样没人能活
Nobody can survive that shit.
噢 但他们能
Oh, but they can.
中尉
Lieutenant,
此处的这些掩体 这里和这里 准确吗？
these bunkers here, here and here, is that accurate?
是的 长官
Yeah, there's three...
是的 长官 也许他们会从后面看 但这就是全部
Yes, sir, maybe a little further back, but it's all...
完全不同 那上边
It's all different up there.
安全 上尉
All clear, Captain.
战士们
Gents,
出发
move out.
是血
It's blood.
糟透了
No shit.
我们已不在堪萨斯了 多萝西
We're not in Kansas anymore, Dorothy.
继续爬
Keep climbing.
这里
Here, come on.
来把你的手给我 让路
Coming through, make way. Out of the way.
- 布朗 - 什么
- Brown. - What?
把这个给杰索普
Give this to Jessop.
下士
Corporal!
来了
Incoming!
趴下
Get down!
他们到底在哪儿 我看不到他们
Where the hell are they? I can't see nothing.
- 隐蔽点 - 该死的在哪儿
- Beats me, pal. - Where the...
军医
Medic!
在这边
We're over here!
把手放在这儿 按住肠子 杰克
Put your hand right here. Put your hand on there, Jack.
快 走 走
Come on, move, move.
来吧 我们帮你找掩护
Come on, we're going to get you under cover.
快 跟着我
Come on, come with me.
跟着我 杰克
Come with me, Jack.
继续前进
Keep moving forward! Move!
看不到任何东西
I can't see anything.
- 是那个吗 - 我不知打哪儿
- Is that one? - I don't know. Just shoot!
好吧 我们上
All right, let's go.
迪诺
Vito!
噢 糟糕
Oh, shit.
- 多斯 迪诺中弹 - 我来了
- Medic! Vito's down! - I'm coming!
好 我在这
Okay. I'm here.
让路
Get out of the way!
你受伤了
You hurt?
我很好
I'm fine.
来吧 我帮你 拉尔夫 呼吸
Come on, I got you, Ralph. Just breathe.
呼吸
Just breathe.
没关系 没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
呼吸 拉尔夫 呼吸
Just breathe, Ralph, just breathe.
我帮你 我帮你 我帮你
I got you, I got you. I got you. Come on.
嘿 嘿 给他一针吗啡再继续前进
Hey! Hey! Give him a shot of morphine and move on.
他挺不了一天
He's not going to last a day.
求你 求你了多斯 别 别
Please. Please, Doss, no. No.
别丢下我
Don't leave me.
别丢下我 请别丢下我
Don't leave me. God, please don't leave me.
我有孩子
I've got kids!
求你 别这样 请别丢下我
Please. Please, don't. Please, don't leave me.
我不会离开
I ain't going anywhere.
我会带你回家
I'm going to get you home.
我会救你 拉尔夫 好吗
I got you, Ralph. Okay?
我会带你回家
I'm going to get you home.
吗啡来了 吗啡来了
Here comes the morphine. Here comes the morphine.
很快就会起作用 拉尔夫
It's going to kick in real quick, Ralph.
我们会转移你
We're going to get you shifted.
担架
Stretcher!
- 起来 继续前进 孩子 - 我受伤了
- Get up. Keep moving, son. - I can't, I'm wounded.
你没事
There's nothing wrong with you.
倒霉 坚持 小子
Shit! Hang on, kid.
动起来 不当士兵就当死人
Move. A sitting duck's a dead one.
上 上 上
Move. Go, go, go!
我们有个优先级
This guy's a priority.
优先级？你还没有分类
A priority? You ever heard of triage?
在我们送他们下去之前 他会死的
He'll be dead before we get him down.
你又怎么知道
You don't know that!
送他下去
Get him down.
可以吗？
All right?
嗯
Huh?
- 好吧 好吧 走吧 - 很好
- Okay. Okay. Go. - Okay. Okay.
没事的 老友 我们会送你回家
It's all right, buddy. We're going to get you home.
军医 救命 救命
Medic! Help! Help.
我觉得若我们看不见他们 他们也看不见我们
I figure if we can't see them, then they can't see us neither.
救命
Help!
我来了 弗兰克 你伤在哪儿？
I got you, Frank. Where you hit?
- 我认为他们只是自作聪明 - 多斯 来吧 来吧
- I think they can see us, smart ass! - Doss, come on, come on.
用手抓住我这儿
Give me a hand here.
趴下 长官
Get down, sir.
在那儿 掩体
Over there! The bunkers.
看到了 最好呆下边 长官
I see them. Better stay down, sir.
发现敌人 正前方
I got 'em, dead ahead.
是的 对 我也看到了
Yeah, yeah I see 'em, too.
准备好所有武器消灭他们
Push in as close as you can. Give them everything you've got.
我会让武攻队从两侧围剿
I'll send in the weapons team to flank them.
抓紧点 你会完好如初 好吧？
You keep that tight, you're going to be right as rain. All right?
我来吧 多斯 我来吧
I got him, Doss. I got him.
你 快
Here you go, come on now.
嘿
Hey.
你干得可好？
You doing okay?
还好
Okay.
开火
And, fire!
趴下
Down!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
- 你 接着打 - 遵命 长官
- You, get on it. - Yes, sir!
马上
Now
掩护他
Take 'em. Go.
开火
Fire!
烟雾弹
Smoke!
掩护
Cover!
上 上 "食尸鬼"
Go, go. Go, Ghoul.
到那个坑里 待着不要动
Get in the hole. Stay there.
上 上 史密提 我们掩护你 闪过去
Go! Go, Smitty, we'll cover you. Leapfrog.
掩护
Cover.
炸药包
Satchel!
- "食尸鬼"- 知道了
- Ghoul! - Clear.
来吧 坚持住
Come on, stick it.
坚持住 食尸鬼
Stick it, Ghoul.
掩护 掩护
Cover! Cover!
狗日的
Son of a bitch.
掩护他
Cover his ass.
军医 军医 救救我
Medic! Medic! Help me.
上
Go!
军医
Medic!
我在这里 用手按住它
I'm here. Put your hand on it.
用手按住它
Put your hand on it!
上 上 上
Go, go, go!
Go, go, go! now
"食尸鬼"
Ghoul.
你没事吧 你伤在哪儿？
You're okay. Where you hit?
你没伤着头没事的
You got a bump on the head, that's okay.
你叫啥名
What's your name?
- 安迪 - 安迪啥
- Andy. - Andy what?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
外号
Also known as?
- "食尸鬼" - "食尸鬼"
- Ghoul. - Ghoul.
"食尸鬼"你没事 你没事
Ghoul, you're okay, you're okay.
很称职 小伙子们 干得不错
Good job, men. Good work.
就此过夜 我们守住本地
Dig in for the night. We hold this spot,
我们明天消灭剩下的山脊
we mop up the rest of the ridge tomorrow.
好了 小伙们
Okay, boys.
给自己找个舒适安全角落或靠近掩体
Find yourself a nice safe hole in or near the bunker.
我们每两小时换次岗
Rotate watch every two hours.
我们不知那边是些啥
We don't know what's out there.
死忠 愚蠢 烂人
Heads down, asses lower.
不说英语的全毙了
And shoot anything that don't speak English.
- 包括"老油条"？中士 - 尤其是他
- Does that include Grease, Sarge? - Particularly him.
我不关心他是否需要尿尿或大号
I don't care if you need to take a piss or a dump,
单独去那边可不安全
it ain't safe to go out there alone.
你到底要去哪儿？多斯
Where the hell are you going, Doss?
那边还有很多伤员 中士
Still more wounded out there, Sarge.
我和他一起去
I'll go with him.
机灵点 注意四周
Be smart. Keep your ears down.
好了 大家找个地儿
All right, let's find a spot.
亨利在首轮15分钟就挂了
Rinnelli and Henry dead in the first 15 minutes,
直接挂掉
just straight off.
是直接挂掉
Straight off.
彼得森 大力水手
Peterson, Popeye.
斯坦福和墨菲
Standford and Murphy.
佩吉 安戈
Page and Unger.
拉斯顿
Ralston.
和平年代子葬父
"In peace, sons bury their fathers,
战争时期父葬子
in war, fathers bury their sons."
别说丧气话好吗
You wanna stop spouting that crap, huh?
这帮不了任何人
It don't help none.
是的
Yeah,
你说得对
you got that right.
但不在此地
Not here.
嘿
Hey,
给我那个
give me that.
嘿
Hey,
嘿 我们找到个腹部伤员
Hey, we've got an abdominal wound.
小伙子需要血浆
This man is going to need some plasma.
- 明白了 - 他和我们一起
- You got it. - Leave him with us.
好了 没事的 他们会救你的
Okay. You're okay now. They got you.
我们找个窝呆呆
Should we find a hole and dig in?
我觉得行
Sounds good to me.
戴上头盔
Put your helmet on.
你要吃那些
You ain't going to eat them?
我不吃肉 你随意
I don't eat meat. Help yourself.
当然了 你不吃
Of course you don't.
她是个不错的女子
That's one heck of a dame.
你知道你有她让我们很受打击 是吗？
You know you're fighting out of your weight class with her, don't you?
是的 我知道
Yes, I do.
别告诉她这些
Don't tell her that.
她不会太喜欢我这样的男人
She'd be much happier with a man like me anyway.
是啊 直到她了解你
Yeah, until she got to know you.
我是个混蛋 有时
I'm an asshole sometimes.
有时
Sometimes?
是的 对 对
Yeah, all right. All right.
这些日本人很卑鄙
These Japs are sneaky.
我来站第一个岗
I'll take first watch, all right?
现在你眯会儿
You get some shut-eye.
地狱之梦
Hell of a dream.
我梦见自己被杀
Dreamed I got myself skewered.
我毫无办法
I couldn't do nothing.
只需步枪
Rifle's just there.
它不会咬人
It won't bite.
对 那么
Yeah, it will.
看看你周围
Look around you.
经历了我们这些遭遇
After what we've just been through,
任何理智的人都会尖叫着找寻武器
any sane man would be screaming for a weapon.
我从未声称自己理智
I never claimed to be sane.
我爸是酒鬼
My daddy's a drunk.
他屡戒屡犯多年 酒瘾缠身
He fought it for years, but it kind of got a hold of him hard.
酒后失态
Made him mean.
至少你知道 何时我曾与
Least you knew him. Mine could have been any one
十人中的任何一位同在 而他们没有一个人该死
of 10 guys, and none of them worth a damn, so...
所以你妈妈养大了你
So, your momma raised you?
我记得她
I knew her,
我记得她 但她把我丢给孤儿院 在我五岁时
but she gave me to an orphanage when I was five.
再没见过她
Never saw her again.
我知如何快速行动
I learned how to hate quick.
但现在我识人更快 我则确实看错了你
I learned how to judge people quicker, and I got you very wrong.
我爸只是经常打我跟我哥 因为日升
My daddy used to beat me and my brother just because the sun rose,
又因为日落 无缘无故打我们
and then whip us just because it set.
我能忍受那样
I could take that...
但当他打妈妈时
...but when he would do it to our momma...
滚开 婆娘
Get away from me, woman!
够了 不再 听清楚没
That's enough. No more. Do you hear me?
扣下那该死的扳机
Pull the damn trigger.
不要 德斯蒙德 住手
Stop it! Stop!
但你并没杀他
But you didn't kill him?
在心里 我杀了
In my heart, I did.
这就是为何我向上帝发誓
So that's why I made my promise to God,
我再也不去摸枪
I ain't never going to touch a gun again.
好吧我不会给你我的 因为你是疯子
Well, I ain't giving you mine, 'cause you're crazy.
狗娘的
Son of a...
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
行动 行动 让你们的屁股离开那儿
Move, move! Get your asses over here.
一起撤
Let's go!
回去 撤退 撤
Fall back, fall back! Go!
他们从地下冒出来
They're coming from underground.
长官 这是贝克6队 请求立即支援
Searchlight, this is Baker Six. Request immediate support.
- 目标是北三零五一五 - 你没注意你在哪儿吗？
- Target is Yoke-Tare-Five-One-Five. - Don't you notice where you are?
是的 我有留意究竟在哪儿
Yes! Yes, I know that's where the hell we are,
但我可不想再呆在这儿
but I don't expect to be here much longer!
我叫了火炮打击
I called an artillery strike.
撤退 行动 行动
Fall back. Move. Move!
撤退 快
Fall back! Incoming!
嘿 兄弟 我在这 我在这
Hey, buddy. I'm right here. Right here.
好
Okay.
掩护我
Cover me.
撤 撤
Go, go!
离开这儿 小子
Get out of here, kid!
过来 孩子
Come here, son.
你知怎做 保持压住它
You know what to do. Keep pressure on it.
不 不需要血浆 把它给他
No! Don't need plasma. Give it to him.
在那边
Over there.
我会没事的 去吧 去吧
I'll be okay. Go. Go.
- 里斯 背他走 - 什么
- Grease! Get Irv's back. - What?
- 收到 好的 - 回头见
- You got it, okay. - See you soon.
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
我们马上行动 来吧 来吧
We gotta move right now. Come on, come on.
来
Change!
人太多了 他妈的快退
There's too many, get the hell out of here!
撤 撤
Move! Move!
- 我很害怕 我很害怕 - 这能止痛
- I'm scared. I'm scared. - It's going to help the pain.
不 不要 不要 你别这样 来吧
No, don't. Don't you do that. Come on.
来吧 史密提留下陪我 我们得一起走
Come on, Smitty, you stay with me. Let's go. We gotta move.
- 嘿 - 是
- Hey! - Yeah.
- 帮我把他送下去 帮我把他送下去 - 好
- Help me get him down. Help me get him down. - Yeah.
来吧让我们行动 来吧
Come on, let's move. Come on.
帮不了你 伙计 他走了
Can't help him, buddy, he's gone.
- 没有 - 来吧 我们要离开这儿
- No. - Come on! We gotta get outta here!
我们走
Let's go!
快 走
Come on, let's go.
快 大家
Come on. Everyone.
离开山脊
Off the ridge!
他要我去哪儿
What is it you want of me?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我听不到你
I can't hear you.
军医 救我 救我
Medic, help me! Help me!
救我
Help me!
好吧
All right.
一切都会没事的 放松 放松
You're in good hands. Easy does it. Easy.
六 八
...six... eight...
十四
Fourteen.
保障这些人的安全
Get these men secured immediately.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
列兵 福特 有多少人？
Private Ford, how many?
只有32个下来了 长官
Thirty-two only came down, sir.
上帝啊
Good Lord.
- 我们四下找找 - 是 长官
- Let's load 'em up. - Yes, sir.
哈利 我是德斯蒙德
Harry. It's Desmond.
我们会医好你 你只需保持呼吸 好吗
We going to fix you up. You just got to keep breathing. Okay?
上校想见你 长官
Colonel wants to see you, sir.
我需要你的吉普
I need your jeep.
你两个留此警戒 提防日本鬼子
You two stay here, keep watch, keep your eyes peeled for Japs.
- 不行 但是 - 留此 警戒
- No, but... - Stay here! Keep watch.
- 遵命 长官 - 遵命 长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
救命 救我
Help. Help me.
当心
Watch out.
我救你
Watch out. I got you.
把手放上面 保持按住它
Put your hand on it. Keep pressure on it.
我会回来 好吗？
I'm comin' back. Okay? Okay.
别离开
Don't leave me
轻些 伙计们 轻些
Easy, fellas, easy.
就放这儿
Here we go.
好了伙计们 一起来 一 二 三
Okay, guys, let's go. On the count of three. One, two, three.
放
Move.
就没 军医来这里
Help, medic over here!
没事 伙计 坚持住
It's okay, buddy, hold it together.
我们来到悬崖边了 埃里克
We're at the edge, Eric.
- 只需坐稳 好吗 - 好
- You just sit tight, okay? - okay
你没事的 埃里克 没事的 伙计
You're okay, Eric. You're okay, buddy.
混蛋 这会起作用
Son of a gun, this is going to work.
每条腿一个 埃里克
One for each leg, Eric.
我们马上帮你穿好 再放你下去
We're going to get you dressed up in a jiffy and get you down.
我救你
I got you.
我现在救你 埃里克
I got you now, Eric.
你得相信我 埃里克
You have to trust me now, Eric.
你得相信我
You're gonna have to trust me.
日本佬
Japs!
等等 我们的人 等等
Hold on, one of ours. Hold on!
快去 快去
Let's go, let's go!
我救你 我救你
I got you. I got you. I got you.
来吧 我救你 你没事了 你没事了
Come on, I got you. You're okay. You're okay.
汉克
Hank,
又一个
another one.
上校 呼叫取消炮击钢锯岭 不能投弹
Colonel, call off the artillery attack on Hacksaw. Couldn't call it in.
还有超过100人在那儿
There's still over 100 men left up there.
告诉他们取消炮击钢锯岭
Tell them to call off the artillery on Hacksaw.
埃布尔 贝克 壹 完毕
Able-Baker-One ,over.
坐下 杰克 我给你喝的
Sit down, Jack. I'll get you a drink.
只是失去掩护
We just lost our cover.
他们要开始了 我们赶紧行动
They're stirrin', we got to move. Come on.
刚好
About time.
他们不断下来
They just keep coming by the...
- 好的 抬起来 - 我抬这边
- OK, OK. Pick it up. - I got this.
多斯
Doss.
救命
Help.
救我
Help
Help me.
你必须要相信我
You're gonna have to trust me.
呼吸
Take a breath.
我们走 伙计
Let's go, buddy.
我们走
Let's go.
杰克
Jack,
你不知道你在那儿的人是死是活
you don't know if your men up there are dead or alive.
没有援军 我们不能回到上边去
You can't go back up there without reinforcements.
- 你会让剩下的人也送命 - 那就给我援军
- You'll end up killing the rest of them. - Then give me the reinforcements.
我没有新人 我没有任何连队
I don't have any fresh men, okay? I don't have any troops.
三个营被消灭在今天
Three battalions got wiped out today.
新兵到这儿还要一天多
It'll take more than a day to get men in here.
我需要他们早点到
I need them faster than that.
没关系 没关系
It's okay, it's okay.
没事了 没事了
It's all right. It's all right.
没事的
Everything's okay.
吗啡 好的
Morphine. It's good.
皮尼克 皮尼克 皮尼克 我是多斯
Pinnick, Pinnick. Pinnick. It's Doss.
我是多斯 安静 安静
It's Doss. Be quiet. Be quiet.
我们来救你
I got you.
- 你伤哪儿 - 我看不见
- Are you hit? - Yeah. I can't see.
安静 安静点
Be quiet. Just be quiet.
现在别动
Hold still now.
我救你
I got you.
抓稳
Hold tight.
弄好了 试着看 试着看
There you go. Try now. Try now.
我以为我瞎了
I thought I was blind!
嘘 冷静 你能走吗
Shh... Keep it down. Can you walk?
我不知
I don't know.
因为我们得离开这儿 好吗 快
We got to get out of here, okay? Come on.
好了
Good. Okay,
我们接住你了
we got you.
We got you.
嗨 泰德
Hey, Ted.
是我 德斯蒙德 我会让你好起来的
It's me, it's Desmond. I'm gonna fix you up.
- 你准备离开这儿 - 我肯定
- You ready to get out of here? - Sure am.
恳请上帝
Please, Lord,
让我再救一个
help me get one more.
Help me get one more.
请让我再救一个
Please, help me get one more.
再一个
One more.
让我再救一个
Help me get one more.
再一个
One more.
让我再救一个
Help me get one more.
再一个
One more.
来了
Coming through.
这些家伙到底哪来的
Where the hell are these guys coming from?
钢锯岭
From Hacksaw.
- 我以为他们已撤完了 - 并非所有
- I thought they pulled out. - Not all of them.
某疯子在那里把伤员从顶上放下来
Some nut's up there dragging wounded from the top.
甚至放下了几个日本佬
Even lowered a couple of Japs.
他们没能挺得住
They didn't make it.
回头直接带给你
Back with you directly.
轻点 轻点
Easy, easy.
满了 出发
All set, move out.
到这儿来 到处都是日本人
Get in here. There's Nips everywhere.
狗娘养的 列兵"玉米秆"
Son of a bitch. Private Corn Stalk.
你还真让人惊喜啊
You are nothing if not full of surprises.
你想要些吗啡？
You want some morphine?
- 想得很 或者你给我一枪 - 好吧
- Hell, yes. That or a bullet. - Okay.
来了
There.
给你
There you go.
好吧
All right,
放松 让我看看
let me see. Let me see.
这样如何？好吧 不坏
How's this doing? Okay, not bad.
让我看看
Let me see.
我会做得比这还要糟
It looks much worse than it is.
但女孩们还是不会吻你
Girls will still want to kiss you.
中士
Sarge,
你可以在此呆一会儿吗？
you okay here for a while?
好的 我还好 尽管离开
Yeah, fine. Get out of here.
我会回来
I'm coming back.
你准备好了？我们走 你跟我 来吧
You ready? Let's go. You and me, come on.
上尉 有事你得瞧瞧
Captain. There's something you gotta see.
整个夜里我们的人被一个个的放下来
Our guys have been coming down in droves all night.
而"好莱坞"在此 我从没想过还能再见此人
And Hollywood's here. I never thought I'd see that guy again.
来吧跟我来 他在这儿
Come on, follow me. He's right here.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell is this?
你好 长官
How you doing, sir?
嘿 "帽子"
Hey, Cap.
上尉
Captain.
- 很高兴看到你 孩子 - 格洛弗上尉 长官
- It's good to see you, kid. - Captain Glover, sir.
你怎么下来的 孩子
How'd you get down, son?
是多斯
Doss.
豪厄尔仍在那儿
Howell's still up there.
什么 豪厄尔和多斯做的
What, Howell and Doss did this?
不 长官 只是多斯
Mostly just Doss.
- 只是多斯？- 只是多斯
- Just Doss? - Just Doss.
对 多斯 那"懦夫"
Yeah, Doss, the coward.
- 你喜欢鞋上的枪 不是吗 - 给我这个
- You're like gum on a shoe, ain't you? - Give me this.
现在打靶太迟了 你不觉得
It's a bit late for target practice now, don't you think?
- 跳上来 - 你开玩笑吧
- Jump on it. - You're kidding.
不 我来拖你
No, I'm going to drag you.
来吧
Let's do it.
- 好没？- 好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
我们走
Let's go.
我们有追兵
We got company.
来吧
Come on.
我们得跳
Arms up.
你在耍我吧？"玉米秆"
You gotta be kidding me, Corn Stalk.
你是结单套 不是结胸罩
"You're tying a bowline, boy, not building a bra."
来吧
Come on.
- 好没？- 好了
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
下去
Get on.
- 放下我 - 是 中士
- Put me down! - Yes, Sarge.
- 中士豪厄尔 - 多斯还在那儿
- Sergeant Howell. - Doss is still up there.
- 到底咋回事？- 他被日本佬尾追
- What the hell? - He's got Japs on his tail.
我们接住他了
We got him.
很好 很好
That's good. That's good.
好 我们接住他了
It's okay, we got him.
好了 多斯
It's okay, Doss.
- 好了 多斯 - 你安全了
- Come on, Doss, - You're safe.
- 好吧 - 多斯 你没事了
- All right. - Come on, Doss. You ok
德斯蒙德 你没事了 没事
Desmond, it's all right, it's all right.
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
放松 放松
Easy, easy.
这儿 来吧
Here, come on.
坐下
Take a seat.
你受伤了
Are you wounded?
没有
No.
大家立即送这名士兵去医疗篷
Let's get this soldier to a hospital tent, right now.
- 来吧 现在放轻 - 放松 放松
- Come on, easy now. - Easy, easy.
腾个地方
Make some space.
伊夫在哪儿
Where's Irv?
- 伊夫 你是说谢克特军医 - 是的
- Irv? You mean, Schecter the medic? - Yeah.
他没能挺住
He didn't make it.
他死于震伤
He died of shock.
没有血浆
No plasma.
抱歉
Sorry.
我只看到一个瘦小子 我不知你是谁
All I saw was a skinny kid. I didn't know who you were.
你比任何别的男人报效祖国
You've done more than any other man could have done
所做的多得多
in the service of his country.
我此生从未如此看错人
And I have never been more wrong about someone in my life.
我希望有天你能原谅我
I hope one day you can forgive me.
我们明天必须回到上边
We have to go back up tomorrow.
我意识到明天是你的安息日
I realize that tomorrow is your Sabbath.
这些人大多数不相信你所信仰的方式
Most of these men don't believe the same way you do.
他们如此相信
But they believe so much
你有多坚信
in how much you believe.
你在山脊上的所为就是奇迹
And what you did on that ridge, it's nothing short of a miracle,
他们想要一块
and they want a piece of it.
没有你 他们不会去那儿
And they're not going to go up there without you.
你到底拖延什么 上尉
What the hell is your delay, Captain?
你应该在10分钟前开始进攻
You were supposed to begin that assault 10 minutes ago!
- 我们在等着 长官 - 等啥？
- We're waiting, sir. - Waiting for what?
列兵多斯完成为我们的祈祷 长官
For Private Doss to finish praying for us, sir.
列兵多斯在为你祈祷？
Private Doss is praying for you?
列兵多斯到底是谁
Who the hell is Private Doss?
我们去干活
Let's go to work.
趴下 趴在地上
Get down! Get down!
立即趴在地上 现在
Get on the ground. On the ground. Now!
躺下 躺下 我有吗啡
Lay down, lay down. I got the morphine.
我们走 我们走 我们带这个人离开这儿
Let's go, let's get these men out of here.
走 走
Go, go.
我的圣经
My Bible...
My Bible.
我的圣经
My Bible...
停下 停下 停下
Stop. Stop, stop, stop. Stop!
我的圣经 我的圣经
My Bible, my Bible, my Bible.
好吧
Okay.
你回家了
You're going home, Desmond.
我们已拿下钢锯岭
We've taken Hacksaw.
等下 等下 德斯蒙德
Hold up, hold up! Desmond!
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
德斯蒙德·多斯把 75 名伤员带至安全地带于钢锯岭战役中
他是第一个"拒服兵役者"获得荣誉勋章：美国"战火中的勇气"表彰
德斯蒙德和多萝西结婚 直至她在1991去世
他是自己的英雄 保有特有的谦虚 将所有的功劳归于他的上帝
我一直在祈祷
I was praying the whole time.
我只是开始祈祷上帝请让我再救一个
I just kept praying, "Lord, please help me get one more."
当我救多一个 我说"好吧 上帝请让我再救一个"
When I got this, I said, "Lord, please help me get one more."
他平淡地说 "真正的英雄们都埋葬在那里"
我认为任何人都是错的
I would say anyone is wrong
若要去妥协他人的信念
to try to compromise somebody's conviction.
我不在乎是军队
I don't care whether it's army
或者是什么
or what it is.
当你持有信念
When you own a conviction,
那不是笑话
that is not a joke.
那就是你
That's what you are.
上尉杰克·格洛弗
即使我对他说那些关于携带步枪的事
Even though I said those things to him in regard to carrying a rifle,
然而他永远不会站在我这边
then he would never be by my damn side at all
除非他拿了枪
unless he had a rifle.
但是从长远来看
But then, in the long run,
发现他是一个活着的最勇敢的人
finding out that he was one of the bravest persons alive.
而让他停止挽救我的生命
And then to have him end up saving my life
则会是对整件事的讽刺
was the irony of the whole thing.
血顺着这家伙的脸跟眼流下
Blood had run down into the fella's face and eyes.
那是当他开始呼喊军医的时候
He was laying there just groaning and calling for a medic.
我从水壶取水 拿出绷带
I took water from my canteen, got some bandage,
我冲洗他的脸
and I washed his face.
当我擦拭
And when I wipe
当我擦拭 冲洗他的双眼 眼睛睁开了
was washing his eyes, his eyes came open.
伙计 他顿时亮了
Man, he just lit up.
他说 我以为我瞎了
He says, "I thought I was blind."
如我没有任何东西
And if I hadn't got anything more out of the war
多于他给我的微笑 我不会得到很好的回报
than that smile he gave me, I'd have been well repaid.
德斯蒙德·多斯以 87 高龄去世于2006年3月